<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The SiteLog</title>
    <description>Log extraordinary sites.</description>
    <link>https://sitelog.llnx.me/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://sitelog.llnx.me/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sun, 08 Oct 2017 10:42:03 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Oct 2017 10:42:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.6.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Decade of Dynamo&amp;#58; Powering the next wave of high-performance, internet-scale applications</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Today marks the 10 year anniversary of Amazon’s Dynamo whitepaper, a milestone that made me reflect on how much innovation has occurred in the area of databases over the last decade and a good reminder on why taking a customer obsessed approach to solving hard problems can have lasting impact beyond your original expectations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It all started in 2004 when Amazon was running Oracle’s enterprise edition with clustering and replication. We had an advanced team of database administrators and access to top experts within Oracle. We were pushing the limits of what was a leading commercial database at the time and were unable to sustain the availability, scalability and performance needs that our growing Amazon business demanded.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our straining database infrastructure on Oracle led us to evaluate if we could develop a purpose-built database that would support our business needs for the long term. We prioritized focusing on requirements that would support high-scale, mission-critical services …&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.allthingsdistributed.com/images/decadedynamo.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;!--description--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 08 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://sitelog.llnx.me/2017/10/08/A-Decade-of-Dynamo-Powering-the-next-wave-of-high-performance,-internet-scale-applications.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sitelog.llnx.me/2017/10/08/A-Decade-of-Dynamo-Powering-the-next-wave-of-high-performance,-internet-scale-applications.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>PostgreSQL 10 Released</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The PostgreSQL Global Development Group today announced the release of PostgreSQL 10, the latest version of the world’s most advanced open source database.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A critical feature of modern workloads is the ability to distribute data across many nodes for faster access, management, and analysis, which is also known as a “divide and conquer” strategy. The PostgreSQL 10 release includes significant enhancements to effectively implement the divide and conquer strategy, including native logical replication, declarative table partitioning, and improved query parallelism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Our developer community focused on building features that would take advantage of modern infrastructure setups for distributing workloads,” said Magnus Hagander, a core team member of the PostgreSQL Global Development Group. “Features such as logical replication and improved query parallelism represent years of work and demonstrate the continued dedication of the community to ensuring Postgres leadership as technology demands…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--description--&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://sitelog.llnx.me/2017/10/05/PostgreSQL-10-Released.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sitelog.llnx.me/2017/10/05/PostgreSQL-10-Released.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Init simple log</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#understanding-top-command&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;top&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; is a monitoring program which is used frequently for tracking process’s resource usage and its activity in &lt;strong&gt;real-time&lt;/strong&gt;, show current tasks being serviced by the kernel, help &lt;strong&gt;discovering&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;diagnosing&lt;/strong&gt; overload or capacity of system by seeing &lt;strong&gt;CPU &amp;amp; Mem usage&lt;/strong&gt;. It’s available under many Unix/Linux operating systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/top-command-optimized.gif&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--description--&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 04 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://sitelog.llnx.me/technical/2017/10/04/Init-simple-log.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sitelog.llnx.me/technical/2017/10/04/Init-simple-log.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>technical</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
